=Within The Grip=
=그립 내부=
=Episode 4=
=에피소드 4=
(Mute Husband)
(음소거 남편)
Yuluo, you've become even prettier.
율루오, 더 예뻐졌네요.
It's you.
당신이에요.
Why are you so mean to me?
왜 나에게 그렇게 못되게 굴어요?
(Gu Xuanji, Second Young Miss of the Gu family)
(구쉬안지, 구씨 둘째 영미스)
Search carefully. Don't let them escape.
신중하게 검색하세요. 그들이 탈출하도록 놔두지 마세요.
My dear sister-in-law, I'll let you handle it.
사랑하는 동서님, 내가 처리하도록 할게요.
How come it's you?
왜 당신이에요?
Why are you so agitated, dear?
왜 그렇게 불안해하니?
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
It's chilly at night.
밤에는 쌀쌀합니다.
You've been out for quite a while.
당신은 꽤 오랫동안 외출 중이었습니다.
You said you and your husband are deeply in love.
당신과 당신의 남편이 말했다 깊은 사랑에 빠졌습니다.
He surely wouldn't leave you out there alone.
그 사람은 분명 그러지 않을 거야 당신을 거기 혼자 남겨두세요.
Therefore, I brought you a cloak.
그래서 나는 당신에게 망토를 가져 왔습니다.
You don't have to act like this when it's just the two of us.
이렇게 행동할 필요는 없어 우리 둘만 있을 때.
But right now, it's not just the two of us.
하지만 지금은 우리 둘만이 아니잖아.
Yuluo.
율루오.
Are you alright?
괜찮으세요?
Examine the bodies. Take them to the authorities.
시체를 조사하십시오. 당국에 가져가세요.
- Understood.
- 이해했다.
Let's go find Xuanji.
Xuanji를 찾으러 가자.
Weren't you expecting that molten iron flower show?
기대하지 않았나요? 그 용철꽃쇼요?
If we miss it this time, who knows when the next chance will be.
이번에 놓치면 다음 기회가 언제일지 누가 알겠는가.
Take a look, young master.
보세요, 젊은 주인님.
Yuluo, this suits you well. Do you like it?
Yuluo, 이거 잘 어울리네요. 당신은 그것을 좋아합니까?
You have a keen eye. This is a Yin-Yang Twin-Blade Dagger.
당신은 예리한 눈을 갖고 있습니다. 음양쌍날검 입니다.
Press the gemstones.
보석을 누르세요.
Pressing the red gem ejects the blade. Pressing the blue one retracts it.
빨간색 보석을 누르면 칼날이 나옵니다. 파란색 버튼을 누르면 취소됩니다.
Only five taels of silver.
은화는 5Tael밖에 되지 않습니다.
What's so special about it? Who gives a dagger to a woman?
무엇이 그렇게 특별한가요? 누가 여자에게 단검을 주나요?
I like it very much.
나는 그것을 매우 좋아한다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You're in a good mood.
기분이 좋아요.
You were just being hunted down.
당신은 방금 사냥당하고 있었습니다.
Now you have the leisure to have tea?
이제 차를 마실 여유가 생겼나요?
Thank you for saving me.
저를 구해주셔서 감사합니다.
I toast to you.
나는 당신에게 건배합니다.
Why were you there?
왜 거기 있었나요?
I'm planning to open a new tavern in the city.
나는 계획하고있다 도시에 새로운 선술집을 열었습니다.
Zuixian Building happens to be for transfer, so I took over.
Zuixian 빌딩은 다음과 같습니다. 이전을 위해 내가 인수했습니다.
I wanted to announce it during the Lantern Festival.
알리고 싶었는데 등불 축제 기간 동안.
But unfortunately, things went wrong.
하지만 안타깝게도 상황이 잘못되었습니다.
For transfer?
이전을 위해?
Yes, I heard the owner is going home to get married a few days ago.
응, 주인이 집에 간다고 들었어 며칠 전에 결혼하려고요.
Why did she have to transfer the tavern for that?
그녀는 왜 그래야만 했나요? 그걸 위해 선술집을 옮겨?
You seem quite concerned about her.
당신은 그 사람을 꽤 걱정하는 것 같군요.
I just find it odd, that's all.
나는 그것이 이상하다고 생각합니다. 그게 전부입니다.
Speaking of which, when is your wedding?
그러고보니 결혼식이 언제야?
A storm is brewing.
폭풍이 몰아치고 있습니다.
Let's set it for
Let's set it for
one month from now.
에 대해 설정해 보겠습니다. 지금으로부터 한 달 후.
Zhaoxi's health condition...
Zhaoxi의 건강 상태...
I can't wait that long.
그렇게 오래 기다릴 수가 없어요.
You'll surely recover soon.
곧 회복되실 겁니다.
One more thing.
한 가지 더.
Master Zhaoxi has just returned with injuries.
마스터 자오시 방금 부상을 입고 돌아왔습니다.
If anyone comes to visit...
누구든지 찾아오면...
It's up to you.
그것은 당신에게 달려 있습니다.
Understood.
이해했다.
In a month.
한 달 안에.
What?
무엇?
So soon?
그럼 곧?
The original date was nearly two months away.
원래 날짜 거의 두 달 남았습니다.
In one month,
한 달 안에
I'm not sure if my Nichang Workshop can finish the garments.
내 니창 워크숍이 맞는지 잘 모르겠습니다. 옷을 완성할 수 있어요.
Don't we have the wedding gown ready?
우리 웨딩드레스는 준비 안 됐나요?
Charging into the funeral hall in your wedding gown was quite a tale.
장례식장으로 돌진 당신의 웨딩드레스를 입는 일은 정말 대단한 이야기였습니다.
But it's better to replace it since it's seen the funeral hall.
근데 교체하는게 나을듯 장례식장을 봤으니까.
(Brother Gu Zhaoxi's Spirit Tablet)
(구자오시 형제의 영혼 서판)
No need.
필요하지 않습니다.
So you refuse to accept my goodwill?
그럼 당신은 내 호의를 받아들이기를 거부하는 겁니까?
That's not it.
그게 아닙니다.
Let us get your measurements for a new set of garments, Zhaoxi.
측정을 해보자 새로운 의류 세트인 Zhaoxi를 구매하세요.
In that case, we'll trouble you, Xuanji.
그렇다면 우리가 문제를 일으키겠습니다, Xuanji.
Don't mention it, Yuluo.
언급하지 마세요, 율루오.
Creating garments for a beauty is a great pleasure.
아름다움을 위한 옷 만들기 정말 기쁘네요.
But Zhaoxi, we haven't seen each other for five years.
하지만 Zhaoxi, 우리는 그렇지 않았습니다 5년 동안 만났다.
How come you don't speak to me at all?
왜 나한테는 전혀 말을 안 하는 거야?
Do you disdain speaking to an outsider like me?
말하는 것을 경멸합니까? 나 같은 외부인에게?
Zhaoxi, you haven't recovered yet. It's all my fault.
Zhaoxi, 당신은 아직 회복되지 않았습니다. 다 내 잘못이에요.
Let me take you back.
다시 데려가겠습니다.
(Wanfeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(만풍각, 구맨션)
So,
그래서,
those assassins fled into Xuanji's courtyard?
그 암살자들은 도망갔어 Xuanji의 안뜰로?
Yes, but I didn't hear any sounds of fighting.
응, 하지만 난 못 들었어 어떤 싸우는 소리라도.
By the time I went for a closer look, the assassins had vanished.
좀 더 자세히 살펴보려고 갔을 때, 암살자들은 사라졌다.
Are you saying that Xuanji sent those assassins?
당신은 말하고 있습니까? Xuanji가 그 암살자들을 보냈다고?
Were they after Xuanji
Xuanji를 쫓고 있었나요
or that shop owner?
아니면 그 가게 주인?
I can't tell.
나는 말할 수 없다.
How is his wound?
그 사람 상처는 어때요?
Wound?
상처?
I asked him to take a medicinal bath.
나는 그에게 약욕을 하라고 했습니다.
Reckless.
분별 없는.
It's time?
시간이 됐나요?
Xuan Qing doesn't know about your injury, but you do.
Xuan Qing은 모른다. 당신의 부상에 대해, 하지만 당신은 그렇습니다.
Let me change your dressing.
옷 갈아입혀줄게
Is this how you treat your husband too?
당신도 남편을 이렇게 대하나요?
Back when I was injured, he comforted me like this.
예전에 부상을 당했을 때, 그는 나를 이렇게 위로했다.
This is a couple's thing. You don't have to understand.
이것은 부부의 일이다. 이해할 필요는 없습니다.
Just focus on playing your part.
자신의 역할에만 집중하세요.
You did well today.
오늘 잘 했어요.
A couple's thing.
커플의 것.
Barging in while someone is bathing
누군가 목욕하는 동안 끼어들기
counts as a couple's thing?
커플의 일로 간주되나요?
I knocked.
나는 노크했다.
Besides,
게다가,
if I hadn't barged in,
내가 끼어들지 않았다면
someone's wound would've festered.
누군가의 상처는 곪았을 것이다.
It occurs to me that you're much more likable
나에게 발생 네가 훨씬 더 호감이 가는 것 같아
when you're quiet.
당신이 조용할 때.
Isn't that right, my mute husband?
그렇지 않습니까, 벙어리 남편?
Tomorrow, I'll teach you how to talk like him.
내일은 내가 가르쳐줄게 그 사람처럼 말하는 법.
So many eyes on the Fufeng Pavilion.
Fufeng Pavilion에 너무 많은 눈이 있습니다.
We've caught 13 people and sent them for interrogation.
13명을 잡았습니다 심문을 위해 그들을 보냈습니다.
But I may need to lie low for a while.
하지만 잠시 동안 누워 있어야 할 수도 있습니다.
That courtyard guard has sharp hearing.
그 안뜰 경비병은 귀가 예민해요.
I tried sneaking in and almost got caught several times.
몰래 들어가려고 했는데 몇 번이나 잡힐 뻔했어요.
Got anything useful?
유용한 것이 있나요?
They're keeping tight-lipped.
그들은 입을 다물고 있습니다.
But rest assured, they'll crack in three days.
하지만 안심하세요. 3일 안에 깨질 거예요.
Three days?
3일?
Kill him.
그를 죽여라.
I confess.
고백합니다.
(Watch the Fufeng Pavilion)
(푸펑각(Fufeng Pavilion)을 보세요)
Master, what about these people?
선생님, 이 사람들은 어떻습니까?
I never keep useless people around. Dispose of them.
나는 쓸모없는 사람들을 주변에 두지 않습니다. 폐기하십시오.
Understood.
이해했다.
Why is that person so fixated on Fufeng Pavilion?
그 사람은 왜? 그래서 Fufeng Pavilion에 집착했나요?
But it seems he's not siding with the Gu family.
하지만 그럴 것 같다 그는 구 가문의 편에 서지 않습니다.
Forget about the spies at Fufeng Pavilion.
스파이는 잊어라 푸펑 파빌리온에서.
Stop patrolling the area for a few days.
며칠 동안 해당 지역 순찰을 중단하세요.
Understood.
이해했다.
(Fufeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(푸펑각, 구맨션)
Things have quieted down these days.
요즘 상황이 잠잠해졌습니다.
You haven't spotted any spies?
스파이를 발견하지 못하셨나요?
None.
없음.
Though someone has been lingering outside.
누군가가 있었지만 밖에 서성거린다.
Exceptional lightness skills.
뛰어난 가벼움 기술.
I haven't been able to track him down yet.
나는 할 수 없었다 아직 그를 추적해 보세요.
Since my "husband" arrived, I've had much more free time.
내 "남편"이 도착한 이후로 나는 훨씬 더 많은 자유시간을 갖게 되었습니다.
Seems I should pay him a visit.
그를 방문해야 할 것 같습니다.
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(광활한 마음, 영원한 의지)
Is this how you knocked yesterday?
어제는 이렇게 노크했나요?
Why did you come so early today?
오늘은 왜 이렇게 일찍 왔나요?
Didn't I tell you I'd teach you how to speak?
내가 말하지 않았나요? 내가 말하는 방법을 가르쳐 줄 건가요?
To imitate someone is not just to look like them.
누군가를 흉내내다 단지 그들처럼 보이기 위해서가 아닙니다.
It requires observation.
관찰이 필요합니다.
Imitate their moves, vocal patterns, and speech mannerisms
그들의 움직임을 모방하고, 보컬 패턴 및 음성 매너리즘
in the shortest time possible.
가능한 한 가장 짧은 시간에.
But you've never met Zhaoxi.
하지만 당신은 Zhaoxi를 만난 적이 없습니다.
So you can only rely on my descriptions.
그러므로 당신은 내 설명에만 의존할 수 있습니다.
In that case, you must avoid people to stay safe.
그런 경우에는 반드시 안전을 위해 사람들을 피하세요.
Like this.
이와 같이.
Zhaoxi has always been ill.
Zhaoxi는 항상 아팠습니다.
Temperatures bearable for most people would burn him.
대부분의 사람들이 견딜 수 있는 온도 그를 태울 것입니다.
So hold the tea saucer when accepting tea.
그러니 차 접시를 들고 차를 받을 때.
That's your first lesson.
그게 너의 첫 번째 교훈이야.
Finish the tea, then I'll teach you how to talk like him.
차 다 마시고 나면 내가 가르쳐줄게 그 사람처럼 말하는 법.
I was going to ask you to blow on it and sip slowly.
너한테 물어보려고 했는데 그것을 불고 천천히 마신다.
But you're quick to improvise.
하지만 당신은 즉흥적으로 행동하는 것이 빠릅니다.
Dear.
에게.
Your hairpin is crooked.
머리핀이 삐뚤어졌네요.
What's wrong, dear?
무슨 일이야?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
It's just that since you arrived,
단지 당신이 도착한 이후로,
things have quieted down in this courtyard.
상황이 조용해졌어 이 안뜰에.
Now let me teach you how to speak like Zhaoxi.
이제 가르쳐 줄게 Zhaoxi처럼 말하는 방법.
Keep your voice light, not too deep.
너무 깊지 않게 목소리를 가볍게 유지하세요.
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪버드나무가 황혼의 미풍에 흔들리네요♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪고대 골목은 시간의 비밀을 지킨다♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪블루스톤에는 생명의 흔적이 새겨져 있습니다♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪떨어지는 꽃잎, 끝없는 그리움♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪그리움은 내 마음속에 남아있습니다♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪치터 현의 한숨 슬픈 이별을 위해♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪